Siddaharth Suman

Senior System Engineer

Objectives

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

About Me

I am a Software Engineer with a total experience of 3.1 years working with FactSet Systems.

I am a self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology.

I am a quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck anywhere.

I possess good communication and interpersonal skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients.

Always willing to help others in need and motivate them and boost their morale.

I like to work as a team and look forward to working with teams where I can contribute with my expertise as well as learn from.

Experience

Dec 2018 -Present

Software Engineer

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

Dec 2015 -

Senior System Engineer

Dec 2018

Infosys Ltd.

- Worked on web applications and mobile applications
- · Worked on development of automated tools and perform testing of web applications
- · Provided middleware support

Aug 2015 -Oct 2015 **Assistant Professor**

Institute of Forensic Science

- · Worked as a faculty for the institute
- · Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses

May 2014 -Oct 2014 Freelancer

Palmate Solutions

Worked as a Backend Web Developer

Jan 2014 -Mar 2014 Intern TechMeet

Worked as an Android Application Developer

Jun 2013 -

Intern

Oct 2013

Opine Solutions

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

Projects

Partner Assessment Portal **Technologies:** Angular 5, Bulma, CSS, HTML, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 8

- Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for salary changes
- Superiors can see a partner's summary, history and other information
- Superiors can provide a salary recommendation for partners based on their assessment
- · Worked directly with client

Profile and Rewards Web Application **Technologies:** Angular 4, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 12

- Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee
- Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports
- Received appreciation from teammates and onsite team as well for good performance

Personal Info

Phone

+91 9920760964

E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

Date of birth

December 18, 1993

Marital Status

Unmarried

Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

Frontend Technologies/ Frameworks

- Angular 5
- Bootstrap
- Bulma
- JavaFX
- Java Swing

Backend Technologies/ Frameworks

Php

Servlets

Mobile Technologies

Android

Markup and Scripting Languages

- HTML
- JavaScript
- CSS
- jQuery
- Php

Programming Languages

- Java
- Typescript
- C++
- Python

Testing Frameworks and Tools

- Selenium
- Coded UI
- HP UFT

Databases

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB

Version Control

• Git

Bitbucket

Geofence and Custom Plugin for Workspace reservation

Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova

Team Size: 10

- · Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office
- Employees can reserve workspaces on a temporary or regular basis as well
- Employees can schedule reservation for future dates and can automatically get a reservation as soon as entering the work area

MobileIron Downloads Report Tool **Technologies:** Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, MobileIron, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS

Team Size: 1

- · Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications
- Enables employees to work on other tasks and not be blocked on creating report manually
- Manual report generation blocks an employee for 1 hour and is prone to human errors
- · The tool takes under 5 minutes to generate the report and is accurate every time
- Received appreciation from offshore as well as onshore team for simplicity and time saving

PwC Application Details Portal **Technologies:** Angular 4, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap **Team Size:** 1

- · Portal for details of applications supported by the support team
- Gives access to internal details of 26+ applications across many territories
- Facility to manage applications list, ping application's soap services and manage relevant documents using integrated Google Drive support
- · Performs automatic healthcheck for all the applications
- · Received appreciation from team

Infosys Buy/Sell App for Android Technologies: Android, Php, MySQL

Team Size: 5

- · App for a buy/sell platform
- · Users can post items for selling and can also see other posts
- · Users can show interest in an item for sale and contact the seller

Education

Sep 2011 -May 2015

Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015

- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for EXTC faculties
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for CMPN and INFT faculties
- Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students
- Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Backend Web Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- · Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group

till Mar 2011

Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

Publications

Feb 2015

Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015

Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)

Tools

- HP
 Application
 Lifecycle
 Manager 9
 Visual Studio
 Management
- IBM Websphere

IDEs and Editors

- Eclipse•
- Visual Studio
- Atom
- Code
- Sublime Text Android
 Studio

Operating Systems

- Windows
- Mac OS
- Linux

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi